vidpaw.com 2019-11-14

# Privacy Policy

We are working hard to ensure user privacy. Keeping users’ information safe and secure is among our highest priorities at VidPaw. Over the years, we have spent a lot of time working closely with applicable data protection laws, and we have already implemented strong privacy protections that reflect their guidance. We are committed to complying with the any legislation and will collaborate with partners throughout this process.

Now, we're making VidPaw GDPR-complaint and trying to meet the requirements of the GDPR, the new data protection law coming into force on May 25, 2018. It affects European and non-European businesses who own services and apps that are accessed by users in the European Economic Area (EEA).

1\. Information We Automatically Collect

We and our third-party service providers (including any third-party content, advertising, and analytics providers) automatically collect certain information from your device or web browser when you interact with the Services to help us understand how our users use the Services and to target advertising to you (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as "Usage Data"). For example, each time you visit the Services we and our third-party service providers automatically collect your IP address, mobile device identifier or other unique identifier, browser and computer type, access time, the Web page you came from, the URL you go to next, the Web page(s) that you access during your visit and your interaction with content or advertising on the Services.

We and our third-party service providers use such Usage Data for a variety of purposes including to diagnose problems with our servers and software, to administer the Services, to gather demographic information and to target advertising to you on the Services and elsewhere online. Accordingly, our third-party advertising networks and ad servers will also provide us with information, including reports that will tell us how many ads were presented and clicked on the Services in a manner that does not identify personally any specific individual. The Usage Data we collect is generally non-identifying, but if we associate it with you as a specific and identifiable person, we will treat it as Personal Data.

2\. Cookies/Tracking Technologies

We use tracking technologies. Cookies and local storage may be set and accessed on your computer. Upon your first visit to the Services, a cookie or local storage will be sent to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. "Cookies" and local storage are small files containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer's browser and stored on your device when you visit a website.

Many major Web services use cookies to provide useful features for their users. Each Web site can send its own cookie to your browser. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. However, VidPaw prompts users at the very first when you visit or use our services in the very first place. You should allow VidPaw to use your Cookies information so that we can offer you a smoother and better experience.

You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent; however, if you reject cookies, you will not be able to sign in to the Services or take full advantage of our Services. Additionally, if you clear all cookies on your browser at any point after setting your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent, you will have to again reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent.

Our Services use the following types of cookies for the purposes set out below:

  * **Analytics and Performance Cookies.** These cookies are used to collect information about traffic to our Services and how users use our Services. The information gathered does not identify any individual visitor. The information is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It includes the number of visitors to our Services, the websites that referred them to our Services, the pages that they visited on our Services, what time of day they visited our Services, whether they have visited our Services before, and other similar information. We use this information to help operate our Services more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity on our Services. We use Google Analytics for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies. It is only used to improve how our Services works. You can find out more information about Google Analytics cookies here: <https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies>. You can find out more about how Google protects your data here: www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html. You can prevent the use of Google Analytics relating to your use of our Services by downloading and installing the browser plugin available via this link: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB).
  * **Essential Cookies.** These cookies are essential to provide you with services available through our Services and to enable you to use its features. For example, they allow you to log in to secure areas of our Services and help the content of the pages you request load quickly. Without these cookies, the services that you have asked for cannot be provided, and we only use these cookies to provide you with those services.
  * **Functionality Cookies.** These cookies allow our Services to remember choices you make when you use our Services, such as remembering your language preferences, remembering your login details, remembering which polls you have voted in and in some cases, to show you poll results, and remembering the changes you make to other parts of our Services which you can customize. The purpose of these cookies is to provide you with a more personal experience and to avoid you having to re-enter your preferences every time you visit our Services.
  * **Social Media Cookies.** These cookies are used when you share information using a social media sharing button or "like" button on our Services or you link your account or engage with our content on or through a social networking website such as Facebook, Twitter or Google+. The social network will record that you have done this.
  * **Targeted and advertising cookies.** These cookies track your browsing habits to enable us to show advertising which is more likely to be of interest to you. These cookies use information about your browsing history to group you with other users who have similar interests. Based on that information, and with our permission, third-party advertisers can place cookies to enable them to show adverts which we think will be relevant to your interests while you are on third-party websites. These cookies also store your location, including your latitude, longitude, and GeoIP region ID, which helps us show you locale-specific news and allows our Services to operate more efficiently. You can disable cookies which remember your browsing habits and target advertising at you. If you choose to remove targeted or advertising cookies, you will still see adverts but they may not be relevant to you. Even if you do choose to remove cookies by the companies listed at the above link, not all companies that serve online behavioral advertising are included in this list, and so you may still receive cookies and tailored adverts from companies that are not listed.

3\. Third Party Application

VidPaw may make third party applications available to you through the Website or Services. The information collected by VidPaw when you enable a third party application is processed under this Privacy Policy. Information collected by the third party application provider is governed by the provider's privacy policies.

4\. Information Use

We use the information we collect, including Personal Data and Usage Data:

  * to enable you to use our Services, to create an account or profile, to process information you provide via our Services (including verifying that your email address is active and valid) and to process your transactions;
  * to provide related customer service and care, including responding to your questions, complaints, or comments and sending surveys (with your consent) and processing survey responses;
  * to provide you with information, products, or services that you have requested;
  * with your consent, to provide you with information, products, or services that we otherwise believe will interest you, including special opportunities from us and our third-party partners;
  * to tailor content, recommendations, and advertisements we and third parties display to you, both on the Services and elsewhere online;
  * for internal business purposes, such as to improve our Services;
  * to contact you with administrative communications and, in our discretion, changes to our Privacy Policy, Terms of Use, or any of our other policies;
  * to comply with regulatory and legal obligations; and for purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent, and as further described in this Privacy Policy.

5\. Securing the Transmission and Storage of Information

VidPaw operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary, and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our users. VidPaw takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or from the Website or Services. Your use of the Website and Services is at your own risk.   

We treat the information you provide to us as confidential information; it is, accordingly, subject to our company's security procedures and corporate policies regarding protection and use of confidential information. After personally identifiable information reaches VidPaw it is stored on a server with physical and electronic security features as customary in the industry, including utilization of login/password procedures and electronic firewalls designed to block unauthorized access from outside of VidPaw. Because laws applicable to personal information vary by country, our offices or other business operations may put in place additional measures that vary depending on the applicable legal requirements. Information collected on the sites covered by this Privacy Policy is processed and stored in the United States and possibly other jurisdictions and also in other countries where VidPaw and its service providers conduct business. All VidPaw employees are aware of our privacy and security policies. Your information is only accessible to those employees who need it in order to perform their jobs. 

6\. Children's Privacy

The Services are intended for a general audience and are not intended for and should not be used by children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and we do not target the Services to children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with information without their consent, he or she should contact us using the details in the Contact Us section below. We will delete such information from our files as soon as reasonably practicable.

7\. GDPR Commitment

VidPaw is committed to partnering with our partners and suppliers to prepare for the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which is the most comprehensive EU data privacy law in more than two decades, and will go into effect on May 25, 2018.

We have been busy at work ensuring that we meet our obligations when handling EU citizens’ personal data.

Here is a highlight of the measures we have been doing:

  * Continuing to invest in our security infrastructure
  * Ensuring we have the appropriate contractual terms in place
  * Ensuring we can continue to support international data transfers by executing Standard
  * We are monitoring the guidance around GDPR compliance from privacy-related regulatory bodies, and will adjust our plans accordingly if it changes.

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have the right to: (a) request access to your Personal Data and rectification of inaccurate Personal Data; (b) request erasure of your Personal Data; (c) request restrictions on the processing of your Personal Data; (d) object to processing your Personal Data; and/or (e) the right to data portability ("collectively, "Requests"). We can only process Requests from a user whose identity has been verified. To verify your identity, please provide your email address or [URL] when you make a request. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

8\. Retaining, Modifying and Deleting Your Personal Data

You may access the information we hold about you. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact us using the details in the Contact Us section below. If you would like to update, correct, modify or delete from our database any Personal Data you previously submitted to us, please let us know by accessing and updating your profile. If you delete certain information you may not be able to order services in the future without re-submitting such information. We will comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Also, please note that we will maintain Personal Data in our database whenever we are required to do so by law.

Please note that we need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such change or deletion (for example, when you enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Data provided until after the completion of such promotion). We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

9\. Contact

If you have any problems about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#73000603031c010733051a170312045d101c1e).
